Divanshu Arneja

Software Development Engineer at Apple

Summary

Current - Software Development Engineer at Apple.

Software Engineering graduate student at San Jose State University.

I have 4 years of IT experience with a thorough understanding of all the stages of the Software Development Life Cycle. I am adaptable, passionate towards my work and a team player.

As an IT professional, I have experience across multiple and varied projects in the IT industry. I have strong Healthcare exposure and worked on various projects related to it. I have knowledge for the areas related to the SDLC including Requirement Gathering & Analysis, Estimation, High Level and Detailed Designs, System Architecture, Implementation, Testing, Deployment, Post Production monitoring and Support. As a valued team player, I enjoy working in a varied role with a combined skill set of business analysis, programming, quality assurance, project management and end-user coordination.

Business Expertise:

- •US Healthcare Industry Business Processes
- •EDI X12 Healthcare transaction including HIPAA 4010/5010 guidelines
- Medicare Business
- •US Healthcare Claims Processing and Adjudication
- •US Healthcare Care Management
- •US Healthcare Authorization and Referrals

Technical Skills:

- •Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Node.js
- •Database: SQL, Mongo DB, DB2.
- •Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Unix
- •Development Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Greenfoot, BlueJ
- •Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, ReSTFul Web Services, D3.js, High Charts, Apache Traffic Server.
- •Big Data: Hadoop, HDFS, Hive, Pig
- •Cloud Platforms: Pivotal Web Services, Cloud9, OpenShift, Amazon Web Services,

•Tools: VMWare ESXi, vSphere, vClient, Salesforce, Selenium, Neoload, Perfecto mobile, Elementool, Bugzilla, Appium, SVN, Project Release Control, HP Quality Center, Github, Jira, MS project, Astah Professional

Experience

Software Development Engineer at Apple

January 2016 - Present

Working with best fruit company. Building some really cool stuff.

Instructional student assistant (TA) at San Jose State University

September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months)

Working as a Graduate Teaching Assistant(TA) for following classes in Software Engineering Department:

- # Enterprise Software Platforms (CMPE 272)
- # Enterprise Distributed Systems (CMPE 273)
- # Web UI Design and Development (CMPE 280)

Job duties include:

- # Assist professor to organize course forums, clarify doubts
- # Prepare assignments, quizzes, midterm and final exam questions
- # Explain assignment solutions
- # Grade assignments & exams
- # Mentor and tutor students

Software Engineering Intern at Yahoo

June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)

- Worked in Yahoo Search YHS team. The team has partnered with various major industry players like Mozilla and AT&T to provide the Yahoo Search capability in their products
- Learned and worked upon how the monetization experiments are implemented on YHS (Yahoo Hosted Search).
- Created a plugin for Apache Traffic Server that helps simplify the UI experiment implementation and minimizes the need to change the code.
- Plugin reads the UI modification from a setup web page based on which it modifies the HTTP Response by changing the HTML code to be rendered on the run time thus making the UI experiments easier and avoiding any code changes.
- Technologies Used Apache Traffic Server, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, C++

Programmer Analyst at CSC

November 2009 - January 2014 (4 years 3 months)

•Worked on US based Health Insurance Application product, Rich experience on HIPAA X12 5010 transactions (837s, 278, 270/271, 276/277, 999 and 835) and ICD10 implementation.

- •Handled large scale projects and consistently rated #1 for outstanding performance and awarded certificates of appreciation from management and client.
- •Developed applications using Java technologies.
- •Experienced in handling complete Software Development Life Cycle (waterfall and agile) and defect root cause analysis.
- •Health Insurance business domain trainer and SME of areas Claims/Billing adjudication, Authorization/ Referrals, Care Management and Membership.

Key Responsibilities:

- •Requirement gathering and Design
- •Providing inputs to business and client on various projects
- •Creating High level and Low level design
- Development and Testing
- •Performing final reviews for deliveries
- •Coordinating user testing and deployment

Major Projects:

- •ICD10 Implementation –
- Enhancement of the various areas of the system per ICD10 mandate by CMS.
- System gap analysis for the areas impacted.
- Created high level and low level designs. Worked towards development and testing activities.
- Completed the project before the set timelines and the client was one of the top 5 insurance companies in US to go live before the mandate date.
- •CMS 837 (Professional and Institutional) Inbound Implementation –
- Created high level and low level designs. Monitored development, testing and deployment activities.
- Modified the inbound implementation of 837 such that it supports the HIPPA 5010 guidelines.
- •CMS 837 (Professional and Institutional) Outbound Implementation –
- Created high level and low level designs. Worked towards development, testing and deployment activities.
- Implemented a system for the outbound implementation of 837 such that the claims data can be sent to CMS for billing purposes.
- Completed the project before the set timelines and the client was chosen by CMS for the pilot testing.

Technical Developer and Business Analyst at Humana

July 2011 - December 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Onsite Team lead, SME, Technical Developer and Business Analyst.

•Directly involved with client and business user. Worked with them on brainstorming on new products that will improve the current application.

- •Gathered requirements from business users for all the projects and identified use cases.
- •Understood and converted business requirement to the technical requirement and enhancing the system based on the needs.
- •Direct communication with the business users, IT leads and third parties throughout SDLC.

Major Projects:

- •Claims Auto-Adjudication –
- Built a system which use to take 837 EDI files and automatically map the billing provider and vendor, claim type using intelligent rules engine and auto adjudicating the claim such that it is ready for payment.
- Created high level and low level designs. Worked towards development, testing and deployment activities.
- •The project increased the daily claim processing rate from 1000 to 10000 claims per day.
- •The accuracy rate of Institutional claims was 100% and Professional claims was 96%.
- •CMS 278 Request and Inquiry –
- Developed a system for 278 Request response and Inquiry such that the authorization can be created from the web portal and the provider can inquire the same.
- Created high level and low level designs. Worked towards development, testing and deployment activities.
- •The whole process was automated and the providers were able to easily able to create authorization in real time.
- •CMS 270/271 and 276/277 data exchange –
- •Data exchange of the medical/patient data with medical partners used for inquiring patient's eligibility and claims status.
- •Created high level and low level designs. Worked towards development, testing and deployment activities.
- •Case management –
- A system to closely monitor patient's medical conditions and provide them effective care as per the needs.
- Created high level and low level designs. Worked towards development, testing and deployment activities.

Education

San Jose State University

Master's degree, Computer Software Engineering, 2014 - 2015

Activities and Societies: International Student Organization, SJSU Bridges, Society of Computer Engineering **Uttar Pradesh Technical University**

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science and Engineering, 2005 - 2009

Divanshu Arneja

Software Development Engineer at Apple



Contact Divanshu on LinkedIn